CARISSA CHIU

Summary

I am a solutions-oriented marketing strategist with a knack for creativity and an eye for design. I value the user experience and have a strong background in content marketing strategy, merchandising, and copywriting. I am a resourceful problem-solver who enjoys improving efficiencies and building processes.

Experience

Internet Brands | Portland, OR (Remote) SEO CONTENT STRATEGIST | 10•2021 – Present

- Optimize and improve SEO for Home and Travel vertical sites: DoltYourself.com and Fodors.com
- Conduct audit of over 40,000 website pages to identify thin content and improve high traffic articles
- Make recommendations to boost rankings through keyword research and Google Search trends analysis
- Write content briefs for editors to elevate existing articles up to SEO standards and grow organic site traffic

Entertainment Benefits Group | Austin, TX (Remote) CONTENT STRATEGIST | 3•2020 – 10•2021

- Led the content merchandising strategy for EBG properties: Beneplace, TicketsAtWork & WorkingAdvantage
- Played a key role in generating commission revenue through strategic partner placements in email campaigns, seasonal campaigns, and EBG site properties
- Analyzed CTR, earnings-per-click, and revenue data to identify and optimize top performers
- Curated a daily list of products to feature on the homepage based on seasonality and consumer trends
- Worked closely with different teams on several site design and CMS improvement projects
- Wrote succinct, compelling copy for partner products and created copy guidelines for consistent messaging across all EBG properties

Austin Bouldering Project/ Black Swan Yoga/ CorePower Yoga | Austin, TX YOGA INSTRUCTOR / VISUAL ARTIST / STUDIO ASSISTANT | 3•2016 - 3•2020

- Create intelligent sequences and provide clear instruction to lead group classes
- Facilitated lectures as part of the leadership team for teacher training programs
- Designed custom, hand-drawn signage to promote special classes, events, and retail sales
- Managed the onboarding, hiring, and scheduling of the CorePower studio team

TextureMedia / NaturallyCurly | Austin, TX MARKETING MANAGER, INFLUENCER RELATIONS | 5•2018 – 11•2018

- Implemented a new influencer program and researched key industry influencers
- Created custom influencer boxes and a new rewards program within a restrictive budget
- Managed communication and email strategy at each stage of the relationship funnel
- Developed influencer contracts and provided recommendations for sponsored sales programs

ASSOCIATE MARKETING MANAGER, E-COMMERCE | 3•2017 - 5•2018

- Created the YouTube Ambassador program; managed the entire project workflow and cross-channel promotion plan
- Implemented NaturallyCurly's first loyalty and affiliate programs; increased referral order revenue by 27% and doubled referral orders within 2 months
- Managed 1,000 product listings across multiple e-commerce marketplaces

CLIENT SUCCESS SPECIALIST | 9•2016 - 3•2017

- Executed aid marketing programs: online ads, giveaway schedules, community reviews
- Devised a cross-functional marketing strategy to launch a new reviews program and gained over 400 responses within the first week
- \bullet Ran and tracked advertising banners to reach goals of up to 1 million impressions

Insight, Enterprises | Tempe, AZ/Austin, TX MARKETING SPECIALIST | 8•2014 – 10•2015

- Managed the delivery of paid B2B marketing programs and relationships with 20 partners
- Successfully collaborated with various teams to implement marketing strategies
- Coordinated the Insight booth managed partner sponsorships for an annual healthcare tradeshow
- Nominated for a monthly employee Insight Values Award

The Wish Ring Project | Tempe, AZ FOUNDER AND OWNER | 9•2013 – 8•2015

- \bullet Created an eCommerce business to benefit the Make-A-Wish Foundation
- Raised over \$2,600 for a Make-A-Wish child through the Adopt-A-Wish program
- Gained a following on Facebook and a national reach within 8 months

Certifications

Google Analytics Course Google Academy | 2022

SEO

Hubspot Academy | 2021

Email Marketing

Hubspot Academy | 2018

Yoga Instructor, RYT 200

Corepower Yoga | 2015

Tech Skills

CMS and web design

Squarespace, WordPress, Wix, Sequoia, custom platforms

SEO and reporting

SEMrush, Moz, Ahrefs, Google Analytics, Tableau

Project management

Jira, Asana, Trello

Affiliate marketing

ShareASale, CJ, Impact, Rakuten

Loyalty programs

Smile.io, CollectLoyalty

Marketing automation

Hubspot

E-commerce

BigCommerce, AmazonSeller, Etsy, Facebook Business

Collaboration

Microsoft Teams, Slack

Basic HTML + Photoshop

Education

B.S. Marketing

Arizona State University, 2014 Barrett, The Honors College Magna Cum Laude Dean's List